# SRIKUMAR ANAND

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

# ABOUT ME CONTACT

Machine Learning Engineer with experience in NLP, Timeseries Forecasting, Yolov5 Object detection, etc. Always excited to implement machine learning solutions. Good at programming. Hands-on experience in AWS compute services, lambda, EB, EC2 etc. Good at data science libraries like pandas, NumPy, PySpark, etc.

Phone: +91-9573223190

Email: anand.srikumar007@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anand-

srikumar-81a498109/

Portfolio: https://anand-sri-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

#### **EDUCATION DETAILS**

- Pursued B. Tech (CSE) from CMRIT of (JNTU Hyderabad) with 69% (2013-2017).
- Pursued Intermediate from SriChaitanya Junior College with 85%(2011-2013).
- Pursued SSC from Gowtham model school with 84% (2011)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2018 - Present

**Software Engineer** 

TechMahindra, Banglore

- Developed an NLP model which can predict the correct Assignment Group and Business service of a given incident/task in Servicenow.
- Performed Data analysis and various hypothesis tests on the energy load curve dataset, and provide data insights to the client.
- Developed a Timeseries forecasting model using LSTM architecture that can forecast co2 emissions in the next 14 days.
- **Created** Streamlit GUI to visualize the time-series forecasting prediction.
- Developed a web application with Flask framework that uses AWS Compute services like **Translate, Transcribe, and Polly** to translate speech and text from one language to another. Also used **Mapbox** API to display maps and navigations.
- Developed Object Detection with bounding boxes model using YOLOV5. Used Custom dataset for YOLOV5.

- **Deployed YOLOV5** trained model to **Sagemaker** endpoint. Wrote Lambda function to detect bounding boxes of an Image and return the result as JSON Object. Streamed the video using **Kinesis Video Streaming.**
- **Helped** in converting DB queries to new Database Schema.

Nov 2017 - July 2018

**Automation Test Engineer** 

Pervacio, Hyderabad

- Created **POM scripts** that follow the user stories and perform various tests
- Developed **POM Framework.**
- Worked on regression and functional testing. Generated results with ITestListeners.
- Used Data-driven approach.
- Performed load testing with jmeter.
- Used various technologies like robotframework, Appium, adb to perform testing. Wrote the testing framework using python and selenium for a different project.

#### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

Programming Languages	Java, <b>Python</b> , JavaScript
Machine Learning	Regression, Classification, <b>NLP</b> , Timeseries Forecasting, Clustering
Cloud	AWS
Data Analysis libraries	Pandas, Numpy, PySpark
Database	SQL
Data Visualization	Matplotlib, Streamlit, seaborn
Frontend	HTML, CSS, JS, React-JS
Backend	<b>Django</b> , Flask
Deep Learning	Keras, Tensorflow
Computer Vision	YOLOV5
Automation Testing	Selenium, TestNG, pyunit, pytest
Problem Solving	Data structures and algorithms

# **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that all the above information provided is true to the best of my knowledge and I am solely responsible for its accuracy.

Date: 29-Jan-2022 Place: Hyderabad

Srikumar Anand